## MUHAMMAD SHAIQ ANSARI

Front-End Developer
muhammadshaiq77@gmail.com
LinkedIn
Blog

Fiverr Profile +92 3368458145

I am a Front-End Developer with a software engineering background and experience transitioning from SEO and digital marketing. I am Passionate about building responsive, user-friendly web interfaces, my mindset is to learn continuously and stay up to modern development practices.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# OCTOBER 2019 – MARCH 2020 FRONT END INTERN, CRYPTEX SOLUTIONS

I worked as a front end developer intern for 5-6 months, working on HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and WordPress.

# FEBRUARY 2021 – JUNE 2022 ERP EXECUTIVE, ARTISTIC MILLINERS

Worked as a management trainee and then qualified to work as an ERP Executive.

### JUNE 2023 – JULY 2024 SEO AGENT, TECNO CLOUD

Worked as an SEO agent, worked on various E-commerce websites around keyword research, content publications, image, and content optimization, etc.

# OCTOBER 2021 – PRESENT (Part Time) COPYWRITER, FREELANCE OUTSOURCER – FIVERR, UPWORK

I am working as a freelance research writer on Fiverr. Recently I lost my Upwork Account. I have worked for many clients from all over the world. I have recently finished working as a how-to article writer for officedemy.com and creative story writer for lensa.com

#### **CURRENTLY LEARNING WEB DEVELOPMENT**

I am actively learning and honing my skills in web development to become a proficient frontend engineer. I have developed a strong understanding of HTML5, CSS3, and Vanilla JavaScript. Recently, I gained hands-on experience with styling frameworks such as LESS, SCSS, Bootstrap, and Tailwind CSS. Additionally, I have started exploring React.js and plan to advance into Next.js soon.

#### **PROJECTS**

(Hobby / Learning projects)

#### 1. Weather APP (JavaScript)

I developed a real-time weather fetching App that works fast, I added some additional small features to add value in project.

#### 2. Cafe App (React)

I created a Café food ordering website and tried to keep it as real as possible. I utilized Context API in it and handled all data and props in an organized and optimized way.

#### 3. Quiz App (JavaScript) - Responsive

I developed a random quiz generator with 20 categories, and some more features, all the additional features are from my mind, not copied from an online tutorial.

#### 4. Text Utility App (React)

I developed a text utility app using React; the idea was from an online tutorial, but I tried to add many additional features on my own.

#### **EDUCATION**

GRADUATED OCTOBER 2020
BS SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, INDUS UNIVERSITY KARACHI

Graduated in OCTOBER 2020 with 3.14 CGPA.

**INTERMEDIATE**: PRE-ENGINEERING KARACHI **MATRIC**: COMPUTER SCIENCE KARACHI

#### **SKILLS**

**Web Development:** HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, LESS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React.js, JSX, API Handling, ES6 Features, DOM Manipulation, Async JS, Event Handling, React Hooks

Databases: MySQL

CMS & Platforms: WordPress

SEO: On-Page SEO

**Technical Writing:** Technical Documentation

**Version Control:** Git (Basics)

### **INTERPERSONAL SKILLS**

- STRONG COMMUNICATION SKILLS
- FLUENT IN ENGLISH SPEAKING
- STRONG ANAYTICAL SKILLS
- SELF STARTER
- PROBLEM SOLVER

### PERSONAL INFORAMTION

CNIC NUMBER: 42501-7802327-5 MARITAL STATUS: UNMARRIED

RELIGION: ISLAM

LANGUAGES: URDU (NATIVE), ENGLISH (FLUENT)

DATE OF BIRTH: 7-DECEMBER-1997

ADRESS: HOUSE # A-55/9, KHOKHRAPAR, MALIR EXT COLONY, KARACHI PAKISTAN